时辰到了
Your time's up.
说过我会了结你
Told you I'd end you.
不  别想
No, not today!
芬奇  我们有个麻烦
Finch, we've got a problem.
里瑟这回是真来狠的了
Reese has really gone off the reservation this time.
我们别无选择了  我们需要根
We're out of options. We need Root.
我知道这是我们唯一的选择  肖女士
I know this is our only option, Ms. Shaw.
我只是希望我们为即将发生的事做好准备
I just wanna make sure we're prepared for what may happen.
里瑟先生  我们拯救生命
Mr. Reese, we save lives.
你拯救生命
You save lives.
并非所有人的生命
Not all of them.
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：阿好  王小麦  somehacker  茶炒栗子
■
翻译：宅女之后  灰灰是菇凉  惠子  幸田实果子
时间轴：Sageibra  阿包包  凭陵新月  Kallen  兜兜爹  烟幕迟迟
■
后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监： 阿好
肖女士
Ms. Shaw.
有新号码了吗
We have a new number yet?
不  没有
No, not at this time.
有一阵子了
It's been a while.
看来城里的人渣们都乖了
Guess the city's scumbags have been behaving.
我们正需要静静
We could use a little quiet.
我可不要静静
I don't do quiet.
所以我才接了这份活儿  以及上一份活儿
That's why I took this job, and the one before that.
我可不太乐意跟你的前雇主
Not sure I appreciate being associated
相提并论
with your former employers,
人家可是想杀了你
who tried to kill you.
这份活儿也没多安全
It's not like this job's any safer.
说到静静  里瑟有消息了没
Speaking of quiet, have you heard from Reese?
他恢复到能站起来后
As soon as he was strong enough to stand,
就一言不发地走了
he left without a word.
知道他去哪儿  几时回来吗
Any idea where he went or when he's coming back?
恐怕这问题只有里瑟先生才能回答
I'm afraid only Mr. Reese can answer those questions.
再见  肖女士
Good-bye, Ms. Shaw.
纽约
科罗拉多州
威士忌
Whiskey.
不停地上
Just keep 'em coming.
-再来一轮  输两倍或翻本  -好
- Another game, double or nothing? --Okay.
你想搞什么
What're you trying to pull?
你以为能捞到我的钱吗
You think you can hustle me?
拜托  只是运气好罢了
Come on, man, it's just a lucky shot.
你现在运气用光了  伙计
Your luck just ran out, pal.
几位  来人
Fellas. Somebody!
拜托  来人救命啊
Come on, somebody help me!
轻点儿  各位
Take it easy, guys!
告诉我这够不够轻
Let me know if this is taking it easy.
住手
Stop!
科罗拉多州
纽约
我稍后要出去采购
I'll be going out for provisions later.
请告诉我你有什么
Please let me know if there's
特别的需要
anything in particular you require.
推车上的一本书就好
Just a book from your cart.
上层  右边第三本
Top shelf, third from the right.
《假神:当代伪经》
False Gods: Pseudepigrapha In the Modern Age?
读书消遣吗  格罗夫斯女士
Doing a little light reading, Ms. Groves?
我知道你很痛苦  哈罗德
I know it's been hard for you, Harold,
发生了这么多事
what with everything you've been through.
现在约翰又离开了
and now even John's left.
不过
Still,
你真不该不理她
you really shouldn't take it out on her.
我确实不知道你在说什么
I'm sure I don't know what you're talking about.
我在说
I'm talking...
你无视她
about you ignoring her.
她有新号码给我们
She has a new number for us.
你怎么拿到的
How did you get this?
你在跟机器联络
Are you communicating with the machine?
我理解你为什么不想干了  哈罗德
I understand why you want to quit, Harold.
但现在不是时候
But now is not the time.
她要我们合作
She wants us to work together.
我知道你有事瞒着我
I knew you were holding out on me.
你非要如此吗
Must you do that?
我们有新号码了
So we have another number.
-我还没决定  -决定
- I haven't decided. - Decided?
我还以为不需要你决定
I didn't think you got to decide.
实际上  需要
Actually, I do.
好吧  那是马上要有决定了
Okay, well, is that going to happen anytime soon,
还是要我先去别处找活儿
or should I be looking for some action elsewhere?
亚瑟・克雷普
Arthur Claypool.
有问题吗  芬奇
Something wrong, Finch?
不  没事  我们该工作了
No, nothing. We should get to work.
你在医院员工数据库里的身份是安・摩尔医生
You're in the hospital's employee database as Dr. Anne Moore.
你确定不想扮下医生吗  哈罗德
You sure you don't want to play M.D., Harold?
我可没当过令人信赖的医生
I never made a convincing doctor,
包括我当医生的时候
Even when I was one.
不  我想我最好还是留在这儿
No, I think it's best if I stay here
尽可能地调查克雷普
and find out as much as possible about Claypool.
那这家伙什么情况
So what are the details on this guy?
他工作生活都在马里兰
He lives and works in Maryland.
直到最近  他一直是家软件公司的IT顾问
Until recently, he was an I.T. consultant at a software company,
鲁尼恩技术解决公司
Runyon Technology Solutions.
他最近的信用卡支出
His most recent credit card charges
是医院的礼品店
are at the hospital gift shop.
他在哪个房间
What room's he in?
这就是古怪之处
That's the strange part.
找不到他在医院
There's no record of him
住院部信息的记录
in the hospital's admissions system.
我找到他了  他在这儿
I got him. He's here.
那他的医疗记录肯定存档了
Then his medical records must be on file.
找到了
I found them.
上边的确诊结果是多形性成胶质细胞瘤
According to this, his diagnosis is glioblastoma multiforme.
脑瘤  有病情预断吗
Brain tumor. Does it give a prognosis?
晚期
Terminal.
要说这家伙是受害人
So, assuming this guy is the victim,
谁会要杀个将死之人呢
who would want to kill a dying man?
我想这就需要我们来查了
I suppose that's what we need to find out.
你今天怎么样  克雷普先生
And how are you doing today, Mr. Claypool?
我觉得是蜜蜂而非蜻蜓
I suspect more honeybee than dragonfly.
你说什么
Excuse me?
生命周期
Lifespans.
蜻蜓四个月  蜜蜂四周
Dragonfly is four months. Honeybee is four weeks.
只要别是蜉蝣
So long as you don't go mayfly on me,
那就没问题
we won't have a problem.
你是新来的吗
Are you new?
还是我又忘记你了
Or have I just forgotten you?
你还没忘记我
You haven't forgotten me.
迟早的事
Give it time.
我的脑子  像是文件系统损坏的电脑
My mind, it's like a computer with a corrupted file system.
我想记起某件事
I know I want to remember something,
去打开文件时  文件却已经损坏了
and I go to open the file, and then it's just gone.
然后突然间
And then, the next thing I know,
记忆如洪水般
memories come flooding back
疯狂涌出
and out of me like a loon.
包括一些不该涌出的
Including a few that really shouldn't.
那又是些什么记忆呢
And what memories are those?
克雷普先生
Mr. Claypool?
你给核心数据做了硬编码吗
Have you hard-coded the essential values?
你说什么
I'm sorry?
每次操作完都必须检查数据库
We must check the database after every operation.
打扰一下  这位医生
Excuse me, Doctor...
摩尔
Moore.
我没在这层楼见过你
I haven't seen you on this floor before.
因为我之前不在这里
That's because I haven't been here before.
-我刚调过来  -从哪儿
- I just transferred in. - From where?
纽约综合医院
New York General.
你是什么科的
What's your specialty?
临床肿瘤和临终关怀
Clinical Oncology and Palliative Care.
你呢
What's yours?
有任何需要就说一声
Let me know if you need anything.
当然
Sure.
芬奇  有政府安保人员在保护克雷普
Finch, Claypool has a government security detail.
你说他是做什么工作来着
What did you say his job was?
IT顾问  这头衔很模糊
I.T. Consultant. I realize that's somewhat vague.
马里兰的地址  模糊的工作头衔
A Maryland address, vague job title,
安保人员
security detail--
我看他有绝密权限甚至更高
I'd say he's got top-secret clearance or better.
他说肿瘤让他的记忆如洪水般涌出
He said his tumor was causing memories to flood out of him,
包括一些不该涌出的
including some that shouldn't.
有可能是
Could be...
有人策划将他灭口
someone's planning on shutting him up for good.
他的安保人员用的是三人楔形站位
His security detail is using a three-man wedge formation.
说明什么
Meaning what?
说明他们是特勤局的
Meaning they're Secret Service.
芬奇
Finch...
这家伙到底是谁
who the hell is this guy?
疑犯追踪
第三季 第十一集
■
访问国家侦察局档案
卫星图像数据库
那是麻雀吗  爸爸
Are they sparrows, dad?
很接近了
Close.
这么着吧
Tell you what.
你帮我修车
You help me with the truck,
我帮你认鸟儿吧
and I'll help you with the birds?
好的
Okay.
引擎熄火了
Engine sleded,
我无论如何都找不出原因
and I can't for the life of me figure out why.
套筒扳手在哪儿
Where's the socket wrench?
我刚放手边儿来着
I had it right here in my hand.
爸爸
Dad?
最近我这脑子是怎么了
I don't know where my head is lately.
你想试试吗
Here, you want to try one?
别弄丢了
Don't lose it.
块块有用
Gonna need every piece.
存在即有理由
Nothing in here that doesn't have a reason to be.
除了灰尘
Except the dirt.
我去接
I'll get that.
抱歉  耗时有点
Sorry, took longer than I--
看
Look.
扯了大蛋的
I'll be damned.
你不应该这么乱拆东西
But you're not supposed to take things apart like that.
明白吗  哈罗德
You understand, Harold?
如果他们不想被人进去
If they don't want you to get inside,
就应该造好点儿
they ought to build them better.
好吧  儿子
Okay, son.
你搞定了
You held up your end.
还想知道那是什么鸟儿吗
You still want to know what kind of bird that is?
有进展吗  肖女士
Any progress, Ms. Shaw?
克雷普的安保人员寸步不离
Claypool's security detail won't leave his side.
你查出什么新东西了吗
You find out anything more on your end?
没有
No.
他少得可怜的网络数据资料颇能支持你的想法
His minimal digital footprint tends to support your idea
他有可能在为政府进行秘密工作
that he did secret work for the government,
但这同时也更难
but it also makes it exceedingly difficult
查出究竟是何种威胁
to determine the true nature of any threat.
我可以搞定那些看门狗
I can get rid of the guard dogs.
只要4.5升的易燃物就行
I just need a gallon of anything flammable.
什么
What?
别担心  芬奇  我们可是在医院
Relax, Finch. We're in a hospital.
肖女士  我相信一定有办法
Ms. Shaw, I'm sure there are ways
不用引发骚动也能接近克雷普
to get to Claypool that do not involve any kind of combustion.
好吧  但我需要个搭档
Fine. But I'll need a partner.
你可以扮医院的管理人
You could be a hospital administrator.
恐怕我做不到
I'm afraid I'm unable to do that.
格罗夫斯女士现在需要特别关注
Ms. Groves is requiring additional supervision at the moment.
等等
Hang on.
有人来看克雷普了
Claypool has a visitor.
女的  年龄跟他差不多
A woman, looks to be about his age.
高个  棕发
Tall, brown hair.
是她吗
Like this?
是
Yes.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
黛安・克雷普
Diane Claypool.
他的妻子
His wife.
记录显示他们结婚二十多年了
Records show they've been married a little over 20 years.
不  不
No--no.
-停  -亲爱的  拜托
- Stop. - Honey, please--
等等  你怎么进来的
Wait, how did you get in here?
-亚瑟  是我  -你怎么进来的
- Arthur, it's me. - How did you get in here?
-病人情况不稳定  -别进去
- The patient's in distress. - Step aside.
他没有不稳定  只是困惑
He's not in distress-- just confused.
你要干什么
What do you want?
没什么  我只是来看你
Nothing! I'm just here to see you.
我不明白  你
I don't understand wh-- no, you--
你没有权限进来
you don't have any authority to be here.
我不能听你说话
I can't listen to you
这是安全戒严楼层
because this is a secure floor,
你没有敏感隔间信息权限
and you don't have S.C.I. clearance.
你不是在工作
You are not at work.
亚瑟  拜托  看看周围
Arthur, please, just look around.
这是病房
You are in a hospital room.
首先
First of all,
你凭什么这么跟我说话
who do you think you are to talk to me this way?
我是黛安  你的妻子
I'm Diane. I'm your wife.
你记不起来了
You just don't remember.
不  不
No. No.
我没时间玩游戏
I don't have time for these games.
我时间不多了
I am on a deadline.
-我得修补  -修补什么
- I have to fix it. - Fix what?
撒马利亚人
Samaritan.
必须要抢先上线  免得
It has to be operational before they--
好了  够了
Okay, that's enough.
"撒马利亚人"  你说什么呢  亚瑟
Samaritan? What are you talking about, Arthur?
他们以为我不知道他们要干什么
They don't think I know what they're gonna do,
但我很清楚他们要干什么
but I actually do know what they're gonna do.
他们想扼杀它  但我不会让他们得逞
They want to kill it, but I will not let them.
我有预防措施
I have taken precautions.
放松  克雷普先生
Just take it easy, Mr. Claypool.
既然知道被骗  就不会被骗了
He is not deceived who knows himself to be deceived.
失陪下  我过会儿再来
Excuse me. I'll--I'll be back.
芬奇  你听到了吗
Finch, did you hear that?
这倒是回答了刚才的问题
That seems to answer the question
克雷普是否为政府工作
of whether Claypool worked for the government.
是啊  什么"撒马利亚人"
Yeah, on something called Samaritan?
听着耳熟
The name is familiar.
我去查查
I'll see what I can dig up.
我看短时间内我无法接近克雷普了
I don't think I'll be getting close to Claypool anytime soon.
不过我可以接近第二选择
But I can get to the next best thing.
虽然不是星巴克  但也凑和
It's no Starbucks, but it gets the job done.
我倒没注意
I hadn't really noticed.
抱歉之前的闹剧
I'm-- I'm sorry about the scene back there.
我早就习惯了  这小意思
Compared to what I'm used to, it's nothing.
不知道你怎么适应的
I don't know how you do it.
我讨厌医院
Me, I hate hospitals.
可我现在得天天在这儿
And now it seems it's where I spend all my time.
他什么时候确诊的
When was he diagnosed?
大约一年前
About a year ago.
症状很明显
The signs were all there.
我只是视而不见
I just didn't want to see them.
他经常在家附近迷路
He was getting lost in the neighborhood.
性情大变
He had a change in his temperament.
克雷普夫人  你知道有谁
Mrs. Claypool, do you know of anyone
想要伤害你丈夫吗
who'd want to hurt your husband?
亚瑟
Arthur?
没有
No.
他是  现在也是  最温柔的人
He was-- is the most gentle man.
问这个干什么
Why would you ask?
他的安保
His security detail.
他们啊  不是
Them. No.
那是因为他的工作场所
They're just here because of where he worked.
在哪儿
And where was that?
国家安全局
The National Security Agency.
他肯定不想我告诉你
He would not want me to tell you that,
但我认为已经没有隐瞒的必要了
but I don't really see the point in hiding it anymore.
你丈夫肯定很重要
Your husband must be a pretty important guy.
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
工作的事他从来不和我说
He never talked to me about his work,
后来我也不问了  然后
So I finally just stopped asking, and then...
我们慢慢连话都不说了
we kind of stopped talking altogether.
说话本来就没用
Talking's overrated.
我是说  那肯定不好受
I mean, that must have been really hard.
真正不好受的是
Not as hard as realizing the person you spent
跟你共度半生的人
half your life with
根本不记得你是谁
doesn't even know who you are anymore.
也许因为这个  我才总来
And I suppose that's why I keep coming back here.
希望亚瑟能记起我是谁
Just on the hope that Arthur will remember who I am,
哪怕只有一瞬间
even for a moment,
他想起来的时候  我一定要在他身边
and if he does, I'm going to be there.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我  该回去工作了
I...should get back to work.
他的安保人员撤了
His security detail is gone.
那克雷普呢
And Claypool?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
这个房间的病人呢
Where is the patient that was assigned to this room?
他去造影了
He was taken to radiology.
芬奇  克雷普的妻子说他是国安局的
Finch, Claypool's wife said he was N.S.A.
这就对了
That fits.
我就知道我听说过"撒马利亚人"
I knew I'd heard Samaritan before.
是国安局机密项目
It was a classified N.S.A. project.
2005年被国会停止资助并关闭了
Congress de-funded and then shut it down in 2005,
正是克雷普现在记忆中的时间
which is clearly the time Claypool is living in.
既然克雷普曾就职于国安局
If Claypool was career N.S.A.,
那他肯定接触过各种绝密情报
then he'd be read in on all sorts of top-secret information.
他现在一嚷嚷别人就知道了
Information he's now shouting for anyone to hear.
我能想到十五家国外情报机构
I can think of about 15 foreign intelligence agencies
会拼命想得到这些情报
that would kill for that intel.
我想也是
That occurred to me as well.
而且威胁可能就来自
As did the possibility that the threat may be
他自己的安保人员
from his own security detail.
为了保护政府的秘密
To protect the government's secrets.
你得接近他
You need to get close to him.
说起来容易做起来难
Easier said than done.
好了  我进来了
Okay, I'm in.
小心点  肖女士
Be careful, Ms. Shaw.
我可没有支援给你
I have no backup that I can send you.
那我快点儿
Then, I'll be quick.
-放松  克雷普先生  -等等
- Relax, Mr. Claypool. - Wait a minute.
垃圾桶里有个注射器
A syringe in the trashcan?
克雷普在造影前
Claypool would have been injected
可能被注射了放射性示踪剂
with a radio tracer prior to his scan.
是硫喷妥钠[吐真剂]
It's sodium pentothol.
东西在谁手里
Who has them?
鲁迪
Rudy.
鲁迪在哪儿
And where is Rudy?
这不是造影  而是审问
This isn't a scan. It's an interrogation.
一切还好吗
Is everything all right?
不
No.
威胁克雷普的人
Whoever the threat against Claypool is,
已经来了
they're already here.
站住  别动
Freeze! Don't move.
肖女士
Ms. Shaw?
就"快"成这样了
So much for being quick.
■
访问国家侦察局档案
卫星图像数据库
你在造什么  儿子
What you building there, son?
这是浮栅晶体管列阵
It's an array of floating gate transistors,
配置成"与非"门
configured as a series of N.A.N.D. gates.
是个记忆系统  看
It's a memory system. Watch.
D
"D"...
A
"A"...
D
"D".
看这个
Now just watch this.
DAD[爸爸]
"Dad."
我在为你制造记忆
I'm making you a memory
帮你记住要关煤气炉之类的事
to help you remember stuff like turning off the stove,
只要我继续努力
And if I keep working on it,
我想我可以让它记住
I think I can make it so it can remember
所有你记不住的事
all the things that you can't.
我们谈过了
Now, we talked about this.
我的问题  你无法修补
I mean, what's wrong with me can't be fixed by you
所有人都无法修补  知道吗
or by anybody else, okay?
但如果我造一台机器
But what if I build a machine
拥有大量记忆  能够思考呢
with lots of memory, one that could think?
就算你能
Even if you could,
就算你能让它有我全部的记忆
even if you could fill it with all my memories,
它也不是我
it still wouldn't be me.
不是所有破碎
You know, not everything that's broken
都可以修补
was meant to be fixed.
你明白吗
You understand?
未知号码来电
-喂  -肖女士
- Hello? - Ms. Shaw?
我猜就是你  你怎么找到我的
I figured it was you. How'd you find me?
我三角定位了离你上个GPS信号最近的手机
I triangulated the phone nearest to your last GPS signal.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
被关在间办公室里
Locked in an office.
伊斯顿拿走了我的枪和手机
Easton took my guns and phone.
我猜到了
I assumed as much,
所以我换了位置以更好地监控局势
which is why I've relocated to better monitor the situation.
-你来了  -我在停车场
- You're here? - I'm in the parking lot.
很好  我想办法出去
Good. While I figure out a way out of this,
这期间你盯着克雷普
you can keep an eye on Claypool.
我想我最好还是待在这儿
I think it best if I remain here
查出是谁给他下的药吧
and try to identify who drugged him.
芬奇  为什么
Finch, why--
我查到了
I found something.
那个装成造影师的女人
The woman posing as the imaging technician,
她在出去时戴了顶帽子避开摄像头
she avoided the cameras by wearing a hat on the way out,
但在那之前
But before that,
她登陆了造影室的电脑
she logged into the imaging room's computer.
伊丽莎白・罗斯
An Elizabeth Ross.
我们得查出她审讯克雷普是为了什么
We need to find out what she was interrogating Claypool about.
我也不知道
I couldn't tell.
我只听到他说了个名字"鲁迪"
I just heard him say the name "Rudy."
摩尔医生
Dr. Moore.
随便你叫什么
Or whatever your name is.
请坐
Please.
给你制造这个假身份的人
Whoever put this identity together for you
业务真是精通啊
really knew what they were doing.
这就引出了如下问题
Which brings me to my next questions.
你是谁  你找亚瑟・克雷普干什么
Who are you, and what do you want with Arthur Claypool?
你好啊  莱奈尔
Hello, Lionel.
芬奇派你来的
Finch send you?
他很担心你
He's worried about you.
靠  我们都担心
Hell, we all are.
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
你以为呢  难道哥这警探是打扑克赢的吗
What do you think, I won my detective shield in a poker game?
眼镜儿也帮了点忙
Glasses helped a little.
回去吧  警探
Go home, Detective.
-莱奈尔  -我听到了
- Lionel - I heard you.
你知道不  这是公共场所
You know what? This is a public place.
我跟你一样有权利待在这儿
I've got just as much right to be here as you.
好吧
Fine.
不过你要待在这儿
But if you're gonna sit here,
只许喝酒  不许说话
you're gonna drink and not talk.
明白吗
You understand?
我没问题
Fine by me.
威士忌  双份
Whiskey. Double.
波本威士忌苏打水  不加波本威士忌
Bourbon and soda. Hold the bourbon.
你是在哪个机构工作
So what agency do you work with?
俄罗斯联邦安全局  中国国家安全部
F.S.B., M.S.S.?
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
你应该去保护克雷普
You should be protecting Claypool.
那造影师给他注射了硫喷妥钠
That tech dosed him with sodium pentothol.
你怎么知道的
How would you know something like that?
你要是干过外勤活儿  也会知道
The same way you would, if you'd done any real field work.
我可以让你非常不好过
You know, I can make things very unpleasant for you.
不好过
Unpleasant?
你们这些特勤局的还真礼貌啊
You service boys are so polite.
追杀克雷普的人
Look, whoever came after Claypool
这次没得手
didn't get what they want.
下次会再来
They will try again.
你还好吧  达德利
You all right there, Dudley?
你看起来不太好
You don't look so good.
芬奇
Finch...
你有没有
any chance you spiked
给特勤局的炒饭动手脚
the Secret Service guy's fried rice?
-没有  -那我们有麻烦了
- No. - Then we have a problem.
是的
Indeed.
我查出谁要杀害克雷普了
I think I've identified the threat to Claypool.
作为国安局的老员工
As a longtime employee of the N.S.A.,
他肯定是那些痛恨
he'd be a prime target for anyone obsessed
政府秘密监视活动的眼中钉
with exposing the government's secret surveillance operations.
然后我就想起了那位造影师的名字
And then I remembered the technician's name.
伊丽莎白・罗斯
Elizabeth Ross.
这是美国革命战争中一位英雄
A name shared with a hero of the Revolutionary War,
"贝琪・罗斯"的原名
more commonly known as Betsey Ross.
美国裁缝师  爱国志士  亲手缝制了第一面美国国旗
美国革命战争
Revolutionary War?
你猜猜可能是谁
I'll give you one guess who that might be.
"时刻警惕"  他们到了
Vigilance. And they're here.
是科利尔
It's Collier.
医生
Doctor?
你干嘛拿着枪
Why do you have a gun?
这些警卫怎么了
What happened to his guards?
我们得走了
We have to go.
为什么
Why?
因为有人在追杀你丈夫
Because there are people coming after your husband.
什么人
What kind of people?
需要拿枪对付的人  去拿他的衣服
The kind you need a gun for. Grab his clothes.
克雷普先生
Mr. Claypool.
-醒醒  -怎么了
- Wake up. - What?
你得跟我们走  先生
You need to come with us, sir.
为什么  我们要去哪
Why? Where are we going?
-换个好点的房间  -不  我不想换房间
- To a nicer room. - No, I don't want a nicer room.
-先生  你真的  -听她的话
- Sir, Sir, you really-- - Just listen to her.
乖乖听她的话
Just listen to what she tells you.
-你是谁  -只要能带你出去
- Who are you? - If we can get you out of here--
你干嘛碰我衣服
What are you doing with my clothes?
放开我  你们俩
Let go of me, both of you,
否则我要开除你们
or I'll have you removed!
他不肯跟我走  哈罗德
He won't come with me, Harold.
拜托冷静
Please calm down.
-哈罗德  我  -亚瑟  拜托
- Harold, I-- - Arthur, come on.
我们得走了
We need to leave.
哈罗德
Harold?
是的
That's right.
终于见到我认识的人了
Finally, somebody I recognize.
我们多久没见了
How long has it been?
很久了
Quite some time.
获取联调局档案资料
■
日期: 1979年11月4日
地点: 奥马哈分部
调查主题: 锡达拉皮兹及洛杉矶区域
DDDDDD干扰电话线路事件
目标: 不明"电话飞客"
调查情况: 未结案
桑德拉的父母出去了
Sandra's parents are going out of town.
酒桶满满
Kegs flowing.
你呢  哈罗德  去不去
What about you, Harold? You coming?
欢迎来到
爱荷华州拉西特市
拉西特商会
人口:2042
他们多久没换标识牌了
When was the last time they changed that sign?
为什么要换呢
Why would they need to?
是啊
Exactly.
巴黎有九百万人口
Paris has a population of 9 million.
谁在乎啊
Who cares?
你不能从拉西特去到巴黎
You can't get to Paris from Lassiter.
我带你们去巴黎
I'll take you to Paris.
[法语]你好  你好
Allo? Allo?
[法语]哪位
C'est qui?
我靠
Holy crap.
你怎么做到的
How'd you do that?
[法语]你是哪位
Tu fais quoi?
哥们  太好玩儿了  违法啦
Dude, that was way too much fun to be legal.
哈罗德
Harold.
上车跟我走
I'm gonna need you to come with me.
是你爸爸的事
It's about your dad.
你们俩认识
So you two know each other?
我跟哈罗德是麻省理工的同学
Harold and I go all the way back to M.I.T.
最强工程师啊
The mighty engineers, huh?
真该看看那时候的我俩
You should have seen us,
信息时代初始的科学小顽童
two young turks at the dawn of the information age.
我们要创造未来  记得吗  哈罗德
We were gonna shape the future, remember, Harold?
记得
I do.
是啊  不过我也记得
Yes, but so do I.
你腿在瘸  是受伤了吗
You're limping. Are you hurt?
没有  之前没治好的旧伤罢了
No, it's just an old injury that never healed quite right.
这边
This way.
哈罗德是我们中最出色的
You know, Harold was the most brilliant of all of us.
要说有人能改变世界
If anybody was going to change the world,
我们知道一定会是他
we knew it would be him.
你后来做什么去了
You know, what did you end up doing?
研究领域是什么
What's your field of expertise?
保险
Insurance.
他有枪
He's got a gun!
那些人是谁
Who are those people?
干嘛开枪打我们  他们想要什么
Why are they shooting at us? What do they want?
-你  亚瑟  -我
- You, Arthur. - Me?
我怎么着他们了
What did I do to them?
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
好了  你们在这里很安全
Okay, you'll be safe here
我去安排下把你们转移出危险地带
while I make arrangements to get you both out of harm's way.
危险地带  怎么  我们有危险吗
Harm's way? Why, are we in danger?
对了  那些持枪人
Yes, the gun people.
这到底是为了什么
What was that all about?
你的工作  亚瑟
Your job, Arthur.
我的工作
My job?
你曾为国安局工作
You did work for the N.S.A.?
别当着她的面说
Not in front of her.
亚瑟
Arthur--
对  我曾为国安局工作
Yes, I worked for them.
估计那些对我们开枪的人
I expect the people shooting at us
也知道
knew that as well.
他们不是要杀你  亚瑟
They're not trying to kill you, Arthur,
至少拿到他们想要的情报之前不会
at least not until they get some information out of you.
什么情报
What information?
你之前在医院做扫描的时候
When you were being scanned at the hospital,
那造影师问你  东西在谁手里
the technician asked you who had them.
-东西  -你回答  "鲁迪"
- Them. - And you answered, "Rudy."
我说了
I did?
你说的是谁
Who were you talking about?
我不知道  抱歉
I don't know. I'm sorry.
没关系  不如休息下吧
That's all right. Why don't you rest?
哈罗德
Harold...
你跟这些事有什么关系
what do you have to do with all this?
我只是听说你可能有麻烦
I just heard that you might be in some trouble.
来  坐下吧
Come on, let's get you settled.
你不该离窗户这么近
You really shouldn't stand so close to the windows.
你们是谁
Who are you people?
保护你和你丈夫安全的人
We're the ones keeping you and your husband safe.
他的安保人员呢
What about his security detail?
不是该让特勤局知道我们在这儿吗
Shouldn't the Secret Service know we're here?
现在  我唯一相信的人都在屋子里了
Right now, the only people I trust are in this room.
你感觉好点了吗
You feeling better?
哈罗德   你还记得
Harold, do you recall
《崛起麻省理工仔》吗
Arise, ye sons of M.I.T.?
我
I--
崛起麻省理工仔
Arise, ye sons of M.I.T.
荣耀归我兄弟会
In loyal brotherhood
天生我才必有用
The future beckons unto ye
白日放歌需纵酒
And life is full and good
崛起崛起再崛起
Arise, and raise
人生得意需尽欢
Your steins on high
今宵酒醒何处
Tonight shall ever be
是夜永铭于心
A memory that will never die
麻省理工仔
Ye sons of M.I.T.
约翰要后悔错过这一幕了
John's gonna be sorry he missed that.
亚瑟
Now, Arthur,
"撒马利亚人"是什么
What was Samaritan?
亚瑟
Arthur.
"撒马利亚人"是非凡的项目
Samaritan is truly a remarkable project.
怎么非凡  说说看
You say it is remarkable. Tell me about it.
它的主要功能是通过分析大型数据集
Its primary function is to detect potential acts of terror
检测出潜在的恐怖活动
through analysis of large data sets.
具体说来  它的能力是
Specifically, it will have the ability
预见行凶者的侵害行动
to anticipate acts of aggression
并提出相应的战略对策
and suggest strategic countermeasures
制止其付诸行动
before the perpetrators can act.
这项目听起来很厉害
It sounds like quite a project.
"撒马利亚人"是革命性的
Samaritan is revolutionary.
不只是因为它能做什么  而是它如何做
Not so much for what it does, but how it does it.
我将系统设计成自主控制
The system was designed to function autonomously,
能通过分析过去运行经验
to continually adapt and upgrade itself
自动改写与升级
through past experiences.
你是说它能记忆和学习
You're saying that it can remember and learn.
对
Yes.
哈罗德  这是我们一直以来的梦想
Harold, it's what we always dreamed of.
"撒马利亚人"是真正的人工智能
Samaritan is a true artificial intelligence.
说得对  亚瑟
You're right, Arthur.
的确非凡
That is remarkable.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
他说的  是我想的那个吗
Is he talking about what I think he's talking about?
看来是
It would appear so.
但那就意味着
But then that would mean--
还有第二台机器
That there was a second machine.
亚瑟造的
And Arthur built it.
收到
Copy that.
找到哈罗德了  现在带他俩回家
I found Harold, and I'm taking them both home now.
获取爱荷华公共安全记录
日期: 1979年11月4日
分局: 爱荷华巡警11局
地点: 爱荷华州拉西特
事件类型: 公民需要帮助
收到
Ten-four.
孩子  他今晚在离家不到一公里处迷路了
Son, he wandered half a mile away from home tonight.
如果气温降到零下怎么办
What happens when it drops below zero?
如果你心有余而力不足
If you're stretched past the point
给不了他需要的帮助
where you can give him what he needs,
也许该给他找个能帮助他的地方了
maybe it's time to find a place that can.
对不起  孩子
I'm sorry, son.
我不知道为什么总是这样
I don't know why this keeps happening.
我总是忘记别人  忘记自己身在何处
I forget who people are, where I am.
没关系的  爸爸
It's okay, dad.
不  有关系
No, it's not.
你拥有了不起的能力  哈罗德
You have greatness in you, Harold.
你的头脑  你的预见
Your mind, the things that you can see--
这不是  爸爸
It's not-- dad--
在这儿太浪费了
And it's wasted here.
你应该去上大学
You should be heading off to college,
而不是照顾个老头子
not taking care of an old man.
我不会离开
I'm not going anywhere.
再说  他们正在造一个电脑网络
And besides, they're building a computer network right now
能够把国内所有的大学都联网
that's going to connect all the universities in the country.
既然我不能离开
If I can't leave town,
我就把信息都弄过来
I'll bring the information to me.
我会有办法的
I'll find a way.
小心  儿子  别太鲁莽
Careful, son. Don't be reckless.
别进你不该进的地方
Don't get yourself into something you shouldn't.
如果他们不想被人进去
If they don't want you to get inside,
就应该造好点儿
they ought to build it better.
走吧
Come on.
你造的机器  亚瑟
This machine you built, Arthur...
"撒马利亚人"  它现在在哪儿
Samaritan-- where is it now?
没在哪儿
Nowhere.
"撒马利亚人"数年前被毁了
Samaritan was destroyed years ago.
2005年
2005.
毁了  为什么
Destroyed? Why?
911之后  政府发动所有的力量
After 9/11, the government had everyone and their cat
想造一个监视一切的系统
trying to build a system that could watch everything.
他们也找上你了
They came to you as well.
是的  我告诉他们  要想如愿
Yes. I told them the only way they could achieve what they wanted
所造的系统要不仅能监视一切
was to build something that not only watched,
还要能理解
but understood what it was watching.
人工智能
An A.I.
我知道你总说人工智能
I know you always said artificial intelligence
不可能  哈罗德  但是
was a fool's errand, Harold, but...
我几乎成功了
I was this close.
几乎
Close?
让"撒马利亚人"成功上线
To making Samaritan operational.
事实上  我没能运行起来
Truth is, I couldn't get it to work.
我本来可以的  只要那些没脑子的官僚
I mean, I could've, if those pinhead bureaucrats
再多给我几周的时间
would have just given me a few more weeks.
我知道我能成功的
I know I could have cracked it.
国会就在那时叫停了你们的项目
And that's when congress shut you down.
不止是我们  是所有的项目
Not just us. All the programs.
星风  海浪  创世纪
Stellar Wind, Tides, Genysis,
未来地图  热那亚
Futuremap, Genoa.
六个月内  全都没了
Within six months, they were all gone.
他们2005年2月25日对"撒马利亚人"下了手
They came for Samaritan February 25, 2005.
说是为避免"侵犯公民自由"什么的
For fear of "violating civil liberties," or so they said.
而你认为另有原因
And you thought there was another reason.
政府想要一个系统  哈罗德
The government wanted a system, Harold.
他们不会轻易放弃
They weren't just going to give up.
他们让国会把我们全叫停
They let congress shut us down,
只留下了"棱镜"那破玩意
all except for that piece of crap Prism,
但那只是掩人耳目
but that was just to throw anyone off the scent.
事实呢
Of what?
他们已经建成了
They'd already found it.
有人捷足先登了
Someone else had got there first.
造出了它
And built it.
我说"喝酒"  苏打水可不算
When I said "drink", I didn't mean club soda.
芬奇还指派你当我的代驾司机吗
Finch appoint you to be my designated driver too?
不  聪明小子
No, smart guy.
我戒酒两年了
I'm two years sober.
为什么
Why?
因为那时我做了不少蠢事
Because back when I was doing a lot of stupid things,
酗酒也是其中之一
drinking was one of them.
然后有个西装混蛋出现在我的后座
And then this jackass in a suit showed up on my backseat
拿枪逼着我帮他  让我审视自己
and forced me at gunpoint to help him and take a look at who I was.
我戒酒的原因
Why'd I quit drinking?
是你
You.
可别得意洋洋
Don't let it go to your head.
再来一杯
Another.
你以为呢  就你一个人痛苦吗
What do you think, you're the only one that's hurting?
我搭档被枪杀了
My partner got shot.
告诉我难道躲在你老爸过去的酒吧里买醉
So tell me how hiding out in your old man's watering hole
能修补好吗
is gonna fix it.
我在八公里开外看到个军事基地的标志
I saw the sign for the army base about five miles back.
本以为这儿可能是你以前的驻地
I thought maybe this was where you were stationed.
直到我看到这张照片
Until I saw the picture.
那相似度
And the resemblance.
我爸被派去越南前就驻扎在这里
My dad was here before he was deployed to Vietnam.
服了四期兵役
Did four tours.
他是真正的战争英雄
He was a bona fide war hero.
-他是阵亡的吗  -不是
- Was he killed in action? - No.
在他工作的冶炼厂
At the refinery where he worked.
回家还不过两个月
Hadn't even been home two months.
是难接受
That's rough.
但这和卡特的事有什么关系
But what's that have to do with what happened to Carter?
没关系
Nothing.
只是证明了在这个世界上无论我们怎么做
Just proves that no matter what we do or don't do in this world,
该出事还是会出事
bad things are still gonna happen.
一切都
It's...
毫无意义
pointless.
无关紧要
Irrelevant.
你怎么能这么说
How can you say that?
你救了很多人  包括我
You saved lots of people, including me.
你说这毫无意义吗
You're saying that was pointless?
好吧
All right.
走
Let's go.
我不走
I'm not leaving.
我没说要离开
I wasn't talking about leaving.
我不会和你打架的  莱奈尔
I'm not gonna fight you, Lionel.
来啊
Come on.
好了  应该可以了
Okay, that should do it.
明天此时  亚瑟・克雷普和黛安・克雷普
This time tomorrow, Arthur and Diane Claypool
就是亨利・麦卡锡和伊莱恩・麦卡锡了
will be Henry and Elaine Mccarthy.
我在多伦多医院给亚瑟安排了病房
I've also arranged a room for Arthur at a Toronto hospital.
我们明天一早就离开
We'll leave first thing in the morning.
如果还有需要我的地方
If there's anything I can do--
够了
Enough!
抱歉  我只是想和他谈谈
I'm sorry, I was just trying to talk to him.
你是谁
Who are you?
能不能别再烦我了
Why don't you just leave me alone?
-亚瑟  没事的  -不
- Arthur, it's okay. - No.
你不能把我困在这儿
And you can't keep me here.
真相无惧质疑
The truth fears no questions.
亚瑟  是我  哈罗德
Arthur, it's me, Harold.
哈罗德
Harold?
这是黛安  你的妻子
And this is Diane, your wife.
我怎么会只记得你  不记得她
How come I remember you and not her?
因为肿瘤影响了你的记忆
Because tumors do mysterious things to memory.
-不  -正如你所说
- No. - It's like you said.
你的文件系统损坏了
Your file system is corrupted.
不  不是的
No. That's not it.
我记得黛安
I remember Diane.
黛安死了
Diane is dead.
我两年前埋葬了她
I buried her two years ago,
在2011年6月12日
on June 12, 2011.
你真的记得
You do remember.
行动
Go.
看来这是不可避免了
I suppose this was inevitable.
逝去的时光是多么奢侈
And seeing as how time is a luxury we no longer have--
赫什
Hersh.
周边安全  夫人
Perimeter is secure, Ma'am.
夫人
Ma'am?
他是你的人
He works for you?
你曾经也是  肖探员
As did you at one time, Agent Shaw.
我猜你一直想见我
I assume you always wanted to meet me.
主控者
Control.
我本来还担心你会影响
I was concerned that you might disrupt
我接近亚瑟
my attempts to get close to Arthur.
不过  你真是相当有用
However, you proved to be quite useful,
从那些误入歧途的隐私恐怖分子手里救了他
saving him from those misguided privacy terrorists
还安排我见到了你的雇主
and arranging it so I could meet your employer,
我可是久仰了
who I've heard so much about.
对了
By the way,
我还不知道你姓什么呢  哈罗德
I didn't catch your last name, Harold.
你想从亚瑟那儿知道什么
What is it that you want from Arthur?
只是情报罢了
Just information.
他最伟大的成就下落何在
The location of his greatest achievement,
"撒马利亚人"
Samaritan.
撒马  不  "撒马利亚人"被毁了
Samar--no. Samaritan was destroyed.
我知道官方说法  亚瑟
I know the official story, Arthur.
我还知道硬盘的事
I also know about the drives.
东西在哪儿
Where are they?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
好了  够了  他说的是事实
All right, stop it. He's telling you the truth.
他不知道
He doesn't know.
我很快会查明的
I'll find out soon enough.
既然我们有幸见面
And since you and I have had the good fortune of meeting,
你可以帮我拿回另一件
you can help me recover something else
属于我的东西
that belongs to me.
你最伟大的成就
Your greatest achievement.
恐怕不行
I'm afraid I can't do that.
你们中会有人开口告诉我我想知道的事
One of you is going to tell me what it is I want to know.
开口的人
And whoever does...
就能离开这儿
will be the one who gets to leave here...
活着离开
alive.
■
死亡  管理员  43.72%
死亡  克雷普  亚瑟  46.11%
死亡[姓名已被篡改]84.98%
化名 肖  萨姆恩
停用
项目  "撒马利亚人"
竞争系统
操作冲突
项目  棱镜
状态：活动中  假目标
未知
项目  棱镜
状态：活动中  假目标
竞争系统: 监控中
操作冲突可能性